Hello.
Hey.
Hello. Hi.
How you doing?
All good, all good in Poland.
We have Easter Christmas right now, so.
OK, yes.
So isn't it the day off for you now?
It's payment on Monday.
Yeah, it it will be on Monday.
OK, good, good.
So on the topics and everything,
how are you?
Do you have anything to reshare if if you
want,
I know that you will pretty cleaned up
Yeah.
the the last assignment the last time,
but still.
Yeah,
so so the previous assignment was like
moving things around.
So I don't think it makes sense to spend
more time on that.
We can like start with with the new one.
OK.
So yeah,
just as we agreed on the today's topic,
so the new assignment,
let's start with a big while I'm still
fresh,
but this is a bit too a bit too generous
to say, but OK.
So yeah,
I see you have the reporting on already.
Thank you.
So the assignment, yeah,
and just as I promised,
the enterprise one this time actually.
So you have an enterprise client.
Potential clients,
a reinsurance firm that is located in the
UK reinsurance means you know,
you probably know that,
but just in case insurance of insurers.
So when they face a lot of risk they have
insurers of their own.
So instead of just having B to C
insurance they they.
They offer B2B insurance and and also
reinsurance.
So they just take the packages off.
So yeah,
this is the details of a business if you
want to can get on. So what's the problem?
So when reinsurer talks to multiple of
their counterparties,
counteragents of just.
Insurance insurances.
What they do is they track packages of
individual insurances and packages and
pensions. They usually call it pensions.
Uh.
Across spreadsheets basically.
So what they have is a lot of Excel work,
Excel magic running and what they then do
is.
They, uh,
send it over to each other multiple times
to reconcile and proof and sign and agree
on everything.
And sometimes it's like a chain process,
like, you know, two, two people in there,
three people in there,
four people in there, et cetera,
et cetera. So it's it's a long.
Complex process.
So what they're looking into is if they
can automate and simplify and also remove
the friction from this process of.
Setting up the trusted boundary for the
process. So when they have,
let's talk about the business flow a
little bit. They have this contract.
The contract is about shifting the risk
from insurance to reinsurance.
So essentially a package that let's say
like the most.
How it's called. Yeah,
let's not put a moral tag on this,
but you know when a person has a life
insurance and there is a probability on
the on their lifespan,
so how long that person will live.
And if the person lives longer,
it's a risk.
So for for for insurance company,
obviously,
because they pay pension for that and
what happens is.
That you as a reinsurance company need to
cover that.
So it's there are a lot of like numbers
going back and forth because of the
tension because you as a reinsurance
don't want to pay extra for something
that is not there.
So for that reason you need to be extra.
Careful and trustful and make sure that
there is not a problem.
So at this moment you have an army of
reconciliation managers doing this Excel
magic.
So now your goal as an enterprise
architect.
Is to come up with a solution that could
solve this,
essentially cut this army in half or like
in four times.
Then instead of let's say 100 of those
people doing manual work,
there'll be 50 or twenty-five people
doing.
Automated work and just controlling the
the the scope and environment.
So for you is to design this how you'll
do this on the limitations other
insurance companies,
other companies are often.
Of another country of origin,
which means that there is multi-country
regional things to take care of or to
think about. This is first thing,
then second thing those companies who are
clients.
Are full external entities,
so it's not like a child branch or
something.
Those are fully separate and independent
entities.
So your goal here is to find a way.
For them to trust each other without
laborious manual work,
because this time manual laborious work
establishes this audit of sorts.
So if you can automate this,
this would be perfect.
And this is basically it.
They are not looking for fancy KPIs.
Obviously they do because they want to
remove people, but it is a big project,
big investment. It's part of their.
Innovation strategy built.
So the the money is not a concern in this
sense,
but it it it's not for you know some raw
KPI to hit.
It is specifically to innovate the
intercompany communication.
Between them.
So in in terms of what's out of scope,
you don't have to think on how to adopt
this from the company's side because
their clients,
they they'll follow them because they
have they bind their bonds by the
contracts and also by you know
essentially monopoly.
Of this thing, so they'll have to adapt,
so you don't need to think about them too
much.
Obviously you'll need to think on how to
onboard them and how to do that.
So the assignment is very open field and
and and complex.
There are multiple ways to approach this.
There is also historical way of how it
was done because it is a real project and
well, it exists by the way, till today.
And so yeah,
the the the things have changed,
but it still exists.
And you know.
We can,
we can talk a lot about this and on the
things I wanted to share about this,
I think it is it and that's it.
So if you have any questions or you want
to clarify something while it's still
fresh.
Feel free.
OK.
So basically the software will be
targeted for that reinsurance company
that is selling. OK, OK.
Yeah, they are the the client, yeah.
And and basically in there we have some
spreadsheet with knowledge we don't have
any.
Any structure of it,
we should be prepared for dynamic
informations there so they can change it.
Yeah, good question. Well, yes and no.
Yes,
because there are a lot of different
spreadsheets and like Excel files,
but now in a sense that there is a
structure,
so the contract that is defined between.
A party and a control party or insurer
and insurer is defined and it defines
like and each contract defines the the
formulas, numbers, percentages,
eligible people to, you know, process.
Amounts of risks,
total possible compensation,
a lot of those things. So in this sense,
when I say Excel Wranglin,
I'll give you a simple example.
So once a month a company.
The insurer company sends a list of
people who still alive,
just as I mentioned about the pension
insurance and the reinsurer tries to
understand who of those people.
Are eligible for the compensation or is
in the risk zone,
so they compensate for that to the
insurer. This is important.
I think we don't talk about regular
people in the sense of people, people.
It is B to B.
So when insurer sends this file,
it's like.
Informational and based on that file,
there'll be proportion in which the
insurer will be compensated.
But we do not compensate people,
so we don't care about them much in this
scenario, so for that reason.
You know, the files are structured.
You know,
it's either tables of people or tables of
money movements or tables of special
conditions for those people and money
movements or just, you know,
contract exceptions because it's also
possible.
Or there is like, you know,
backtracks and adjustments because last
month there was a mistake.
So this month we have to fix it and just
manually move the funds.
But in a sense of a structure,
there is definitely one.
Mhm.
If it makes sense.
OK. And the company,
the area of of work is like people
related. So we don't, we don't insurance,
I don't know ships or or buildings.
No, we don't send the billing server.
So it's so unless I I misunderstood your
Good.
question,
but we as a insurance company or they as
our clients don't send the checks to the
payrolls to people.
What they do is they they have this
contract and.
Mm-hmm.
The contract is paid once a month or,
you know,
rarely on special occasions to reconcile,
you know,
reconciliation dates basically when the
specifics fund some, you know, money.
Move to the neither direction,
either one or other direction based on
the conditions of the contracts,
based on the data statuses, etcetera.
So in this sense,
it's quite rare to do those things.
And if that was your question, no,
you don't need to integrate with some
payment service provider to.
To do that, you know.
OK,
so from the Eagle point of view it will
be solution for document management so I
can provide some data and the client
could like reply or also.
Provide some input and it should be more
or less dynamic,
so the company is not constrained by some.
Constraints basically,
but still for each document we should be
able to provide some structure.
Well, well, basically yes.
To rephrase you a little bit and to help
you on this one from the Eagle point of
view,
it is a file management system always,
but with the details on the file content
because.
The reinsurer sends the contract in.
So contract defines the basic rules,
basically like those are the laws of this
specific engagement.
Then insurer sends the.
Sends the files like to simplify the case
each month.
So what they do is like each month they
send a file with the data.
The data is usually about the their
package. Packages is people.
You know,
like the the the insurance people.
And based on the that file,
what happens is you take a contract,
you take a file, you merge it somehow.
I don't know how that's your job.
And then what you do is.
You.
Define based on this encounter how much
to pay.
So now I cave it here because how
contracts are obstruct in our discussion,
just not to go deeper because otherwise
we'll be lost.
What I want you to focus on in the
infrastructure layer and trust because I.
Like highlighted it a couple of times
that you know they're from different
countries,
they're different independent companies.
They inherently don't trust each other,
neither one or another.
So they used armies for that,
like people and regulators and short
parties.
Somehow to do that.
So what you have to do is to first and
foremost build a solution that is
trustful,
trustworthy somehow by all the parties.
How you'll do that? Well,
there are multiple options,
but how you'll do that?
Is up to you,
but you know they're just for you to
focus on.
So this time it's not about the business
logic and app,
it's mostly about the infrastructure and
what's important, trust boundaries.
You know how to establish them,
how to make them verifiable,
how to say that the the file is the one
that.
Is trustful and want to be trusted.
How to say that you know the changes are
rightful at like how to say that the the
money that was released and issued in One
Direction like are correct, you know?
All those questions you'll need to answer.
So your focus here is on the
infrastructure and all the trust solution,
which is a little bit different from what
we've done before,
but I believe this is the the, the,
the beauty of it.
So you don't have to actually do do the,
you know,
tight contract calculations because we've
done.
Contract calculations, but it's, you know,
not boring,
but it is simple in a way that you know
you take formulas and you count.
It was done in Excel previously,
so it is just a right?
So it's not for you now.
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Well, well,
there were a lot of complex formulas and
like to to give you a throwback from that
project,
people will talk about those managers,
lump sum people.
They claimed that it's impossible to move
the logic outside of Excel files.
You know, it's too, too hard, you know,
like it's too.
Dangled in and like even once it's in
Excel,
it's like some dark dark Excel magic.
So we will not be able to write any code
based on that because it's just dark
Excel magic. So yeah.
And were you successful in that?
Well, yes, we were able to. Yes,
it was a like project that really was an
innovation project.
We had an insider in the company who
invited us, Martin Actors.
He left that company long ago,
but you know he was.
It was a person who would you usually
call a visioner.
So he had a lot of crazy ideas.
So he asked us to help. I was in the team,
first team of five, you know,
people to to build and then.
And today the account is like 70 plus
people,
the the the biggest financial accounts in
details, which is not bad.
I long since left left it because there
there was not a job for me in the in the
sense that.
You know, everything is business as usual.
No, nothing. It's just, you know,
regular old stuff. So ask to be released.
And I was released like five years ago
now already. So yeah.
Mm-hmm. OK.
Oh yeah,
any other questions regarding the
assignment?
Most probably that's it for for right now.
Most probably I will come back with some
Yeah, it's fine. Yeah, please do.
follow-up questions. Yeah,
but I need to like first read about the
the the the domain,
let's say then first first investigation
OK, yeah, no worries. Yeah, yeah.
What what to do and how? Yeah,
about.
Exactly.
this is part of your job. OK, so yeah.
And like on the second topic now to tell
you some lessons and and things,
I think I can tell you something about
the one account or credits it used to
call.
So it also happened a couple of years ago,
I guess like four years ago now, maybe,
maybe more, I don't actually remember,
maybe five. So what happened there is.
It is a financial account or used to be
working on the payments and what they
wanted is they wanted a tool of sorts yet
again to allow the internal.
Audit because they are payment service,
they want to be auditable.
So what they wanted is to control the
payments that they have to decrease as
usual,
as you already know by our discussions,
to cut middlemen and to lower the prices
of the payments they issue to.
Their users.
So the usual thing here is to develop
something internally.
The like downside of this is that if you
build something like that yourself,
not using something like,
let's say you need to be auditable and
adhere fully to.
To all the PCI things, you know,
if if people use the credit cards and
they send you the the money and then you
have to, you know,
have that somewhere in the accounts of
yours.
So you know a lot of regulations there.
And it was during the end of blockchain
hype.
So I was originally invited there as
someone with the blockchain expertise and
what they wanted initially is to have a
blockchain as a core, so.
To this day,
I joke that my biggest achievements in
that account is that, you know,
I managed to.
Well,
managed to convince them that blockchain
is not needed because they are single
party.
They are internal to themselves and they
don't need all the overhand that
blockchain brings. You know,
it was the kind of the consistency issues.
With the performance issues with
everything.
So like like point A in this story.
So like you never take what your client
says for granted because what they
explicitly wanted is blockchain.
But it it was not the tool for them to to
fit in. So basically that's it then now.
Continued on that topic.
So we've started the discovery and still
we wanted to audit is to well,
we wanted to to have an auditable tool
still and next.
Idea what we had is like OK,
let's look for other tools and at those
times there were no mature solutions for
that. There was QDB from Amazon.
If you know what QDB is,
essentially QDB is.
A single account,
persistent storage for data,
so the blockchain,
but for one essentially like immutable
storage,
mutable database kill DB and that was 1
candidate to to do that. Another was.
Uh.
I forgot the name of it.
Huh.
Go something, not Quorum, but.
The database over. So yeah,
it's actually doesn't really matter
because it's bad,
but there was a database written in
Golang that also adheres to all those
benefits of auditable and immutable tool.
And yeah,
because of on my like background,
because I came from Go,
I use this natural affinity towards the
tool and after some short non elaborated.
Discover around it, you know,
trying it for a couple of days basically.
What happened is we agreed to use it and
we started using it and initially it was
fine, you know.
Let me just so, so, so it's not lost.
Let me try to find it.
Because it should be 1.
Um.
Not ocean, not pocket, not Prisma.
Option.
3.
Not covenant, not build, not frost,
not go cache and go in UDB. Yeah,
I'll drop you the I'll drop you the
GitHub.
Yeah,
so in UDB essentially mutable database
and it also was both SQL and key value
storage.
So it really did everything we saw what
we need,
but you know and initially it was fine
because in the dev.
There is not much a thing to stress test
it,
but as we moved to production and we were
quite successful in production actually,
so we moved fast.
What happened is we started seeing some
issues with it,
so the issues related to the.
The consistency and you know how
transaction were managed because we were
using.
net as a main tool because the core
application used.net. So we did use this.
Instruments through the gateway
essentially.
So that brought number of limitations and
we tried to find them different ways
because this is an open source.
I've contributed to it to fix some of the
minor things.
And that was accepted.
It was very funny because I've received
an offer from them, you know,
if I want to help them, I rejected it.
But still, even even with that,
we were unable to.
We're unable to fix that.
So in the end there was a lot of fuss and
what we had to do is to create a
migration to Postgres and just agree to
use Postgres because you know,
like this is this is the moral of the
story. But yeah, we've done that.
We've designed the migration and achieved
that.
So now really the moral of the story is
that you know the first step that we've
done is that removed blockchain from the
equation was actually good,
but we needed to to go an extra step and.
It's to look for extra tools.
Maybe at that point of time I didn't know
that there is a plug in for Postgres that
actually allows achieving the same
immutability thing. Now I know,
but you know, not five years ago and.
Basically,
when you have some specific requirements,
you know sometimes when it's something
that is not for every day's use,
and because of that you expect to see
some strange tools or some.
You know, as a cervical approaches be.
To be just mindful of them, you know,
be be be careful and try to look for
convenient solutions and like you know,
like a second moral of the story or not
the moral of the story,
but you know that even the generic
guideline you know simpler is very often.
Better.
You know there is a joke running joke on
LinkedIn and elsewhere that you know you
when you have an architect in your
project, you basically, you know,
write your own sentence with over
engineers,
over complicated solutions you know when
you have.
Yeah,
I don't know like 3 caches on your login
page,
but basically your job is to ensure that
there is no over complication and there
is a tool that clearly addresses.
An issue because you know it's both on
the infrastructure level and tool
selection and also on the level of code
too that sometimes engineers are.
Well,
taken away by the ability to write some
complex code.
I remember like a long time ago,
like closer to 10 years,
that the people were fascinated by Scala
and how you can write.
You know, a very elaborated, complicated,
not even Lambda,
but actually Monada of the whole things
Monad to, you know, do something.
I don't really understand what and do it
in one line. Yes, you could, but.
Also why? You know,
it's like during one of the my projects I
saw a person who tried to download parts
and then process data from.
Excel spreadsheets actually in in
parallel threads while it's, you know,
just a report.
So there is no time pressure on it
because it is a report and you know if
it's a daily report,
as long as it completes in less than 24
hours, it's fine.
You know, basically. So yeah,
this is it on this model of the story.
If you have something to ask about this
specific case, we could,
or if you have any source of yours to
share, please feel free.
Uh, so you're regarding the database. Uh,
in my previous project we had like a
architect.
Well, historical.
In our project he really pushed to have a
Postgres in the end and we were using
some cracks DB so it is also time bounded
database so you can travel through time.
And they faced a lot of issues with it.
And yeah, we were,
Well.
we were using it as Postgres and yeah,
in the end it worked just fine and so.
Yeah, well.
So this is about like using custom
database while it isn't required and
Postgres might.
Do the same job with custom plugins as
you said and they really have a bunch of
features,
for example for geolocation that we were
using for or plan to use for that mobile
application.
So there is also plugging for geolocation
in Postgres.
And so there's no need to like using
different one if it's not necessary.
OK. Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, that that that is quite true. Yeah,
please.
Hey.
And with the blockchain,
it was the same project.
So it was during that blockchain hype and
it was a very early that they already
faced some performance issues.
So it was like a bank for a banks.
And while onboarded four of them,
they said OK,
we can onboard like few more and that
will be it. We cannot handle more.
That is true. That is true. Yeah.
Also to share a small story about the
blockchain, but it's not about blockchain,
but building your own thing that we have
a project that, you know, luckily,
fortunately or not,
but it ran out of funds.
Of funding.
And the core premise of that was to,
you know, create a blockchain,
but not in a sense of, you know,
create an application that uses
blockchain. No, no,
it's actually was to create the fastest
blockchain in the world.
So we had a client who was very yet again
visionary.
So what they wanted is to build a
platform to trade and tokenize the parts
of the.
Well, buildings and flats and everything.
So you know it's it can be traded as an
asset they wanted and you to use your own
home as your own bank essentially what
was their idea.
So if you want to get a coffee you you
trade in some of square inches or
centimeters you know like.
Perfect. You know,
so you know the idea and what they what
they wanted for this to work is they knew
the amount and this is like the common
knowledge that sometimes useful to know
for an architect.
You know,
the average amount of transactions that
Visa or MasterCard, let's say,
process throughout the day, like per hour,
per minute, per second.
And it's like for a second, it's like 100.
Hundreds, thousands of tens, it's public,
basically. So visa requests per second.
Yeah, like 2465 transaction messages, 65,
000 per second. It's a lot. Not, not, not,
not a blockchain is able to, you know,
achieve that speed.
So what we've done is we've started our
own investigation.
On the existing protocols,
none of them fit except of couple of very
fringe and less explored.
So we still try to achieve those and even
when we use those fringe.
They were slower than expected.
So what we've tried is we've tweaked the
numbers, we've simplified the protocols.
You know,
like essentially what we've done is we
were trying to fight against the very
nature of a blockchain because it's
complex and in computation on purpose.
And when we've done that,
like then we've run the first grid on
multiple machines.
We actually managed to run it for a short
seconds,
but in a while it all fell down due to
desynchronization.
Which is expected because just as I
mentioned, you know,
there are some rules of the blockchain
that keep it together. So yeah,
that project ran out of funding,
but you know, the idea was crazy.
You know,
I'm not saying about the business
implication, but.
You know on how to fight it.
So you know that it's the same moral of
the story.
So don't try to fight against the nature
of the tools you're using or bound to use
because you know the tokenization.
But yeah,
so these are two stories from my end.
So if you have any questions, please.
Ask them. If not,
I'll have to drop a little bit early
because I have to prepare for the next
call, but yeah.
Mm-hmm. OK, yeah.
So most probably that's it.
OK, yeah, on the on the assignment,
that one is complex and abstract.
A.
So please send me your questions as you
usually do and I'll answer them as
synchronously so you don't have to wait
the next session.
Mhm.
Mhm, OK.
OK. Thank you.
Yeah. Thank you. Bye.